<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Portfolio webstite for Andrea Gerards</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Portfolio webstite for Andrea Gerards</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analysing weather and temperature anomalies</title>
      <link>/projects/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project1/</guid>
      <description>OverviewWhen researching global climate changes and temperature data, you will often read about the “temperature anomaly.” That is the difference between the long-term average temperature (sometimes called a reference value) and the temperature that is actually occurring. In other words, the long-term average temperature is one that would be expected; the anomaly is the difference between what you would expect and what is happening.
A positive anomaly means that the temperature was warmer than normal; a negative anomaly indicates that the temperature was cooler than normal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brexit</title>
      <link>/projects/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project4/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe UK referendum on EU membership on 23 June 2016 is a key moment for European (dis)integration. Even though the outcome had been expected to be tight, in the days running up to the referendum bookmakers and pollsters predicted the ‘Remain’ side to win. Many observers were left puzzled and keen to understand who voted for ‘Leave’. Various newspapers and blogs quickly reported plots that relate the referendum vote to key characteristics such as the age profile of the population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYT Mask Use Acceptance</title>
      <link>/projects/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project3/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionIn some American neighborhoods, it’s hard to spot even one person outside without a face covering. In others, the odds of seeing many maskless people are quite high.
Public health officials believe that face coverings can substantially slow transmission of the coronavirus, which is spreading rapidly in many states. But face coverings work best if they are adopted widely, and that is not the case everywhere. The accompanying map shows the odds of whether, if you encountered five people in a given area, all of them would be wearing masks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voting in the UN General Assembly</title>
      <link>/projects/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project2/</guid>
      <description>Let’s take a look at the voting history of countries in the United NationsGeneral Assembly. I will be using data from the unvotes package.I will make use of the tidyverse and lubridate packagesfor the analysis, and the DT package for interactive display of tabularoutput.
DataThe unvotes package provides three datasets I can work with: un_roll_calls,un_roll_call_issues, and un_votes. Each of these datasets contains avariable called rcid, the roll call id, which can be used as a uniqueidentifier to join them with each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s play!</title>
      <link>/projects/project00/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project00/</guid>
      <description>library(grDevices)rsnake &amp;lt;- function(x=8,y=8, auto=NULL, plot=TRUE, detailed=FALSE) {bodycheck &amp;lt;- function(newhead) {if(newhead[1] &amp;lt; 1 || newhead[1] &amp;gt; x || newhead[2] &amp;lt; 1 || newhead[2] &amp;gt; y) return(FALSE)return(sum(sapply(1:length(snake), function(x){identical(snake[[x]], newhead)})) == 0)}newfood &amp;lt;- function() {while(!bodycheck(food &amp;lt;&amp;lt;- c(round(runif(1, min=1, max=x)), round(runif(1,min=1, max=y))))) FALSErx &amp;lt;- food[1]ry &amp;lt;- food[2]if(!plot) return()rect(rx-0.1, ry-0.1, rx+0.1, ry+0.1,col=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;)}gameover &amp;lt;- function() {newheads &amp;lt;- matrix(rep(c(snake[[1]][1], snake[[1]][2]),4),ncol=2,byrow=TRUE)newheads[,1] &amp;lt;- newheads[,1] + c(1,-1,0,0)newheads[,2] &amp;lt;- newheads[,2] + c(0,0,1,-1)for(i in 1:nrow(newheads)) if(bodycheck(newheads[i,])) return(FALSE)return(TRUE)}drawsnake &amp;lt;- function(prevsnake=NULL) {if(!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who am I?</title>
      <link>/projects/project0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project0/</guid>
      <description>OriginsMy name is Andrea Gerards and I am half German and half Italian. I grew up in Italy, in a city close to the Austrian border called Bolzano. I have played Basketball for over a decade but always used to practice other activities including tennis, football, volleyball and golf.
EducationI have attended a high school in scientific studies in Bolzano. My passion for economic matters led me then to join Bocconi in Milan for my Bachelor’s and I am now happy to be part of the LBS community.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
